# ADRIAN SEVITZ

Over 2 decades of expertise shaping technical strategy, leading product and engineering teams and building software products.

Co-founder of vzaar, developed the business from initial concept and inception through to acquisition (by DaCast Inc). Grew from zero staff and pre-revenue to through to profitability. Led and executed the exit process, including board and shareholder management.

Technology Domain Lead at Smart Pension successfully managing large transformation and development projects, cost reduction programs, with a focus on increasing security profile, reliability and value proposition.

A clear approach to software development focusing on how to deliver growth and value. Knowledge and experience of breaking down complex problems into achievable solutions and working with cross functional engineering teams to deliver this.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Jun 2020 - Present Smart Pensions Limited

Smart Pension is a workplace software pension platform that leverages a modern technology stack to make a cost competitive pension platform for our partners. Focusing on streamlining enrollment and pension management for employers, advices whilst delivering an modern pension portal for employees

May 2021 - Present Director: Technology

Lead the Technology Domain for a multi-client international pension software platform. The domain's goal is to provide the underlying enablement technologies that support and allow the pension related functionality to be developed and delivered.

Role oversees the end-to-end process, strategy, discovery, and management of these teams and to ensure the timely delivery of these solutions. Responsibilities include ensuring my team's objectives align with the company's broader business plans and global growth ambitions.

- Managing all product staff whilst working with engineering managers and directors to ensure timely delivery of business and development goals
- Stakeholder management across the business including risk, legal, security and procurement teams
- Creating and realising the technology delivery roadmap. Prioritising for business value and objectives
- Presenting the quarterly Technology Domains strategic plan for approval and execution by c-suite

### Successful projects include

- Transitioned front-end client applications across all clients to a new technology framework and design library, supporting over 1.5m members, employers and advisers.
- Introducing multilingual support including Right to Left and Arabic in the Middle east.
- Transitioned compute from Heroku to to AWS improving security, increasing stability & reducing costs by 20% whilst enabling future saving opportunities of a further 40%.
- Delivered new bespoke data analytics product for clients including transitioning the data warehouse, reducing development time of new client reports from months to weeks.
- Conceptualised & developed a new approach resulting in ability to launch new platforms 12x faster

- Addressed Security Teams' highest priorities including introducing AV scanning.
- Ensure GDPR compliance under tight timeframes unblocking other contractually committed releases

#### 2020 - 2021 Platform Architect

Program and technical guidance across the platform providing strategic and tactical input

- Discovery workshops with current and prospective clients
- Evaluating and advising on platform architecture, security and technologies
- Evaluated payroll vendor solution for retirement product. Engaged stakeholders to pivot to optimal solution, reducing vendor and build costs by 6 figures.
- Proposed and introduced Tech ops approach within IT to increase engineering efficiency

#### 2008 - Aug 2019 vzaar Limited / DaCast Limited

Founded modern SaaS video platform hosting millions of videos and serving billions of viewers

#### 2017 - 2019 Chief Executive Officer, vzaar limited

- Led complete company vision and strategic direction.
- Directed all activities for a \$2.5m P&L, 20 employees, and 3 countries including forecasting, budgeting, finances, legal, human resources, recruitment and facilities
- Executed strategic plan and established operations and a WFOE in Beijing, China.
- Planned and delivered the search for exit opportunity, engaged broker, prepared all pitch & sale assets
- Met with potential buyers, sold deal to board and shareholders, negotiated final outcome
- Executed sale process and acquisition by DaCast, including financial, legal & technical due diligence.
- Led the operation integration of DaCast with vzaar and initiated future strategic and business plans

#### 2008 - 2017 Chief Technology Officer, vzaar limited

- Execution of the development plan and roadmap as well as the long-term product vision
- Recruiting and hiring of all technology, design, product and support staff
- Managed day to day operations across the business and all vendor relationships
- Maintained controlled low infrastructure costs whilst increasing usage by 10x multiples
- Worked with board on fund raising and involved in all investor pitches, raising over £5m in investment

#### 2007 - 2008 eBay Inc, Senior Manager

- Analysed site experience, got buy-in on underperforming areas and provided actionable next steps.
- Relaunched UK home page experience with new customer-centric approach

#### 1997 - 2007 Accenture, Manager

- Sainsburys: Investigation into poor performance and churn on online shopping platform leading too Stakeholder approval to proceed with improvement project. Lead on functional and usability design changes; Developed scope, requirements and implementation plan.
- Chellomedia: Manager of application architecture for internet video on demand platform in NL
- Virgin Media: Led and delivered on engineering projects for NTL, C&W and Telewest helping to create and deploy their digital television platforms (which enabled the merger into a single entity in 2006)

# **EDUCATION**